{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1. Which of the following statements is a correct statement?",
      "answers": {
        "a": " PI controller improves steady state response",
        "b": " PD controller improves transient response",
        "c": " Both of the above",
        "d": " None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. What is the relationship between the steady-state error, gain and the tendency of oscillations when the controller is supposed to be under the proportional action?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Steady-state error increases with an increase in gain and oscillation tendency",
        "b": "Steady-state error decreases with the decrease in gain and oscillation tendency",
        "c": "Steady-state error decreases with an increase in gain and oscillation tendency",
        "d": "Steady-state error increases with the decrease in gain and oscillation tendency"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. Full form of RTD is",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Resistance Thermistor Detector ",
        "b": "Resistance Temperature Detector",
        "c": "Round Temperature Detector",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Thermistors are very _____ for narrow range applications and slightly _____ for wide temperature ranges",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Unstable , Linear ",
        "b": " Nonlinear , Unstable  ",
        "c": "Linear , Nonlinear",
        "d": " Nonlinear , Linear "
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. What is the value of gain, if the proportional band setting is 156%?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "0.87 ",
        "b": "0.95",
		"c": "0.64",
        "d": "0.39"
        
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Which one of the following controllers increases the order of the system by one?",
      "answers": {
        "a": " P controller ",
        "b": "PI controller",
        "c": "None of the above",
        "d": "Both of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. What is the disadvantage of proportional controller?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Provides a constant steady state error  ",
        "b": "Improves stability of the system",
        "c": "Improves steady state error",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "8.  The _____is a device that changes its electrical resistance with temperature?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Thermopile",
        "b": "Thermostat",
        "c": "Thermistor",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }, 
    {
      "question": "9. Automatic controllers operate on the difference between set point and measurement, which is called",
      "answers": {
        "a": " Error ",
        "b": "Bias",
        "c": "Feedback ",
        "d": "Offset "
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "10. A plant is controlled by a proportional controller. If a time delay element is introduced in the loop then ______",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Gain margin remains the same ",
        "b": "Phase margin remains the same",
        "c": "Gain margin decreases",
        "d": "Phase margin decreases"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}

